Okay, Professor Kaeser, we can start now whenever you are ready.
Okay, thank you.
So I'm going to share my screen.
Perfect.
You can see it.
Yeah, I can see it.
Okay, awesome.
So yeah.
Thank you very much.
I would like to welcome all of you also from my side.
Um, I guess I have already been introduced.
My name is Christian Kaiser.
I am professor at University of Albstadt-Siegma-Wing in the textile department.
We are educating textile and garment engineers.
My scientific background is that I am a
engineering cybernetician, which means actually that I'm a control engineer or systems engineer
and I got in touch with the textile topics, during my studies at the University of Stuttgart.
What I would like to give you a short overview and some insights is how our university introduced
glow3D in our curriculum.
Because before I joined Albstadt-Siedmaring University in 2018, 3D was no focus point at our teaching classes.
My personal background, I'm already 3D user since 2010, so I would say one of the first users in Europe.
And actually, as I'm not from garment and textile industry, it was not hard to convince myself,
because if you go to mechanical engineering, aerospace and all the other mechanical engineering disciplines,
3D development and 3D simulation is state of the art.
So to me, it's pretty obvious that 3D development and 3D visualization of garments is also something
which should be implemented in the future.
And I hope that we can do that in the textile industry as soon as possible.
Starting with what we did to implement 3D classes based on CLO at our bachelor's degree,
the starting point was the winter semester in 2019 to 2020.
There, we started introducing 3D models.
We started using CLO 3D within our bachelor courses.
Actually, at this time, it was starting with one course.
And pretty soon, a colleague of mine, which is a designer, and me,
we entered the academic workshop of CLO in Munich, Germany.
This was our start, where we did refine our
already pre-existing,
understanding of 3D simulation with this type of software.
Both of us were skilled in terms of other softwares,
because we are using multiple 3D softwares at our university.
But this workshop was really some kind of game changer,
because after that, we could really speed up our tutorial database,
our online courses, as well as enhance the quality of our presence teaching.
Pretty soon after this, we also had our first students 3D project in 2020,
and our second one just the next semester.
And after this curriculum, we started optimizing our tutorial database.
Perhaps something I should tell you, because I'm a control engineer,
I personally live in a feedback loop,
which means,
every kind of teaching, every type of action I'm responsible for,
means we start with some kind of steering impulse,
which means like starting with curriculum and stuff like this.
And we optimize each of our lectures on a regular basis,
based on the feedback of the students,
based on proceedings in the market,
be it software-wise or be it more application-wise.
And this means that mid of 2021,
we had our first big run-through,
which we used to optimize our tutorial database
and also go for a second academic workshop at CLO in Munich.
In fact, for us, the second workshop wasn't that necessary anymore,
because we were pretty skilled in what we were doing,
but twofold.
This was super helpful.
The first part is networking.
I guess all of you experienced that 3D,
unless it's not yet that new anymore,
is still some area of teaching where we are lacking routine.
The other part is there are super active players,
super skilled players.
And if you want to push forward,
it's super helpful to build up your own network.
Being it in industry,
being it in the academic world.
And this is the reason why we entered the CLO academic workshop in 2021.
Once again, because this also helped us to go next level.
What were the challenges that we were facing?
The main challenge is to embed 3D in current curricula.
Because I guess all of you experienced this issue.
You are having current lessons.
And you have to focus in the areas that are important to you.
Be it the sewing parts,
being it the textile parts,
being it in the CAD,
being it as 3D,
which is something new entering the curriculum,
which means you really,
really have to focus.
For us,
the general focus points were,
first of all,
the mechanics,
the digital sewing,
and then going to two application areas,
which are the virtual fit and the 3D design part.
What you are seeing on the right side is work of my students in 2021,
where they,
based on the materials,
I was teaching them,
had to experience their own small projects,
like developing a pattern in 2D,
transferring the data.
In this case,
we were using Electra's 2D system to CLO,
to arrange patterns,
to do the first swings,
and then debugging,
like optimize the braping of the garment,
optimize the pattern sizes to the fit.
And also identify,
this is something you're seeing on the shirt of Gabriela Schön,
summer semester 2020,
on the backside,
which areas are facing inconsistencies,
or that's the other part.
We are linking this also to our sewing classes,
are equivalent to what you were facing in the real life.
I already talked about embedding 3D.
And I really do choose this word by purpose,
which means embedding is something different to a add-on.
What I face in European teaching is that many universities
understand 3D skills as add-ons to the traditional textile and garment skills.
In my opinion,
this point of view is pretty mistaken.
It's not an add-on.
It's just a basic skill.
So like the students are able to sew,
like the students are able to develop patterns by hand,
and build up other competencies,
3D is the standard skill.
This means that our students do not have any choice
when it comes to the 3D classes for a pretty long time.
The skills,
we really want to transfer it to our students.
This means that in the bachelor degree,
we are having the digital construction lessons
that split between pattern,
pattern means construction by hand,
CAD,
which means construction by computer-aided design,
and the 3D simulation of exactly these CAD patterns.
This allows the students to have a close feedback loop.
What I develop by hand,
I see how to do this on the computer,
and I see the result of the drape in 3D on a defined human model.
We do this like on a standard level in digital construction 2
and go in more advanced 2D and 3D skills in digital construction 3.
In digital construction 4,
we do a shift of focus.
There we go on high-end simulation and rendering
because having the digital twins of your garments
on the technical part is the one thing,
enabling visual communication
and high-end visual communication is the other super important part.
Having this so far enables
the students to use 3D as a standard skill in projects.
These projects might be project lectures,
but might also be projects they are having in different lectures.
For example,
we are having lectures
facing on more uncommon sewing and tufting solutions
like welding,
like gluing and stuff like this,
where the students are,
for example,
in rain jackets.
And
since we started implementing this type of curriculum,
the students use 3D for 3D prototyping
of the garments that they are developing on this lecture on their own.
So this means 3D is a real standard skill.
And the professor having this lecture,
he is actually no 3D expert.
He also did not foster
the students to do so,
but it was the choice of the students on their own to do that.
And this is something which makes me really proud
because regularly you try to push industry exactly in this way,
like a industry garment manufacturer,
please do first of all digital prototyping
before you go to the real prototype.
And that's something that my students,
they really do this on their own purpose.
For sure,
I have to admit that for the lectures that were in advance,
we really,
really did push the students
and we really did raise awareness when it comes to this.
But
in the meantime,
it's still the students adopting this and using these skills.
And
I would so far say 3D is a
standard skill
for our students,
standard skill latest in the third semester
that they can use in further lectures as design lectures,
3D print design,
3D knit design,
alternative sewing technologies and whatever else.
I already said
a other success factor
was the CLO academic workshop.
For me personally,
it was less the teaching on the mechanics of the 3D software,
but more the really excellent tutorial database.
I mean,
the CAD database that you are equipped by CLO in these workshops
because this really,
really helped me to build up tutorials and curricula for my students.
In a super lean and handy way
and expand these teaching materials on my own purpose.
So I really,
really would like to advise you to make use of offers like this.
These are super,
super helpful.
Another success factor in our case is the team.
I guess you already heard I'm more of the techie.
So
design and aesthetics are by far not my core competencies.
I do not care if a shirt is pink or yellow when it comes to the technical part,
because for me,
it's just the question,
did you do your job on a technical basis,
right or wrong?
My colleague,
Maria Baum,
she's the creative part.
She is a design professor.
She really,
really helps the students to use the means and tools that I'm teaching the students in a super creative way to realize super,
super
difficult designs or innovative designs,
which means like we both have each other as enabler and can accompany the students right on the right level.
To have the best learning experience,
depending on which type of application you're looking at.
The other part is
I built up a online teaching platform for all the softwares that we are using at our textile classes at our university with video play,
video play,
i would say pure conviction like marina and me we are super super convinced that it's not the
question if you do a 3d it's just the question how good you do because it is in my opinion one
of the most important tools for industry for the next five to ten years um the other part
nevertheless and this was even more important during corona to enable the students in the
best way possible to choose their own teaching experience this is something we are optimizing
on a regular basis like each semester we are enhancing and improving our tutorial database
as well as our scripts as well as our teaching materials for presence lessons and presence
teaching here you see a super super simple
example for a 3d design class um i guess all of you are more or less facing um the trust issues
in industry like does 3d have any positive impact on my working or not um in this case you just see
a regular t-shirt like a we call it white shell which we draped with different textures like mesh
knit jersey shiny textures and you see that um the appearance
of the t-shirts completely depends on the type of material that you're using which is something
i really really focus on making the students understand this type of value because
if you are for example a t-shirt shirt trousers manufacturer if you are capable of building up
white shell libraries this really speeds up your process lens
okay this is like light speeding what you are doing so far because so far um industry is either
working on swatches or is making prototypes including the latency you need until these
prototypes are manufactured and by this it's just like a drag and drop operation having these
designs for a skilled student of mine and i guess also for skilled students of yours it's like
minutes once you have your stimulation and even
building up the simulation is the question of minutes not like hours what i really also do
teach the students is the ingredients of a good simulation we are aware of the fabric we are aware
of the pattern we are aware of the human model like the 3d human model and when it comes to the
fabric it is teaching the students the different types of maps and their type of use and how to
improve them
sharp maps that are not blurry that are that type of brilliant to go for later on high-end rendering
or option two you're just in the sketching use your smartphone or whatever camera else have a
short snippet use it and assess the worth of the design or not here you see also work of my
students actually all of the things that you're seeing here is work of my students you see it's
from 2021 actually my students are right now way better than they were at this time but we are
using also multiple tools surrounding to the traditional 2d cad tools in q3d in this type for
example fusion 360 here in fusion 360 we are we were making some kind of buckles and stuff like
this we are also working with blender
um to bring hardware or hardware components together here for example some kind of carabine
and we bring all of that together in clo for example in the bachelor's classes
to make the students understand how to make hardware and trims if you do not have them
how to import different different formats like objs fbx gltfs from other frameworks within
the
3d simulation framework because this is also based on my systems engineering background
you have to think in frameworks the best software not being framework capable or you
do not use it in a framework is just like digitalization of one step but it's about
the question how to digitize the entire steps that you are facing and that you are in need of
here you see work in progress how the students um improve the
from their sketch to the final simulation and this is something that we are really really
accompanying with our students closely and teaching them how to do this
but most of the time based after like standard teaching on their own projects
here you see what we used as a basis like for example the carabine was in avatar
the
pattern pieces were garments and for example here the button was used as a trim
here you see other results of students projects this is a backpack simulated in clo
that we later on also rendered on keyshot because
i really also want my students to understand you can do high-end visualization within 3d tool but i
think also way more expensive with 3d but there are also options to even more enhance your work
outside of the traditional 3d garments tools and the question is depending on your application
which type of visualization quality you need um being honest and co you are always super fast and
your visualizations are really really good if you have to go for the last percent um then other
might also be of use here you also see a different type of bags focusing on garments does not mean
to leave out the other textile products for example this semester we are starting a lecture
where the students develop a backpack in 3d and they also manufacture this backpack in 3d
without sewing just with gluing and with welding so to really push forward the idea of digital
prototyping and advanced manufacturing techniques here you see an other example of one of my
students work also from 2020 this is something i'm super proud of because what you see here
is the students have the task to go on digital and technical marketing purposes within their
and you see here on the right side of the puffer jacket you really see the funnels
of the downs which is super hard to visualize visualize um when you are doing like real
manufacturing real prototyping but which is super super easy when you go in the 3d simulation of the
garments um and this was one of the best work of my students at this time i'm really really
happy about it
the creativity the detail level of the simulation as well as the ideas how to present the products
we also go for knits because weft and warp knitting is one of the
focus teaching areas at our university as well
i think i have to tell you that in alpstadt we were in a knitting cluster in the southern part of
germany um which means that we have machine manufacturers for weft and
warp knitting right beside our doorstep and i guess all of you know that the visualization
of knitted garments is like champions league when it comes to 3d visualization you see
that there are inconsistencies when it comes to the gradient from the mesh of the weft knitting of
on this part to the RIPS on that part.
I guess you know this issue.
Most of the customers don't.
What you also see is that you can really, really
go on high-end visualization.
And if you do not know that it's a simulation,
I guess it comes pretty close to what you can also
show to the end customer, especially when you go,
for example, to web visualization like 720p.
These are other examples of my students' work.
Here's some rain jacket.
There's some training and competition outfit.
Most of the time, especially if the students are
skilled in the later semesters, they just
do get a task in terms of you have
to simulate garments that have a certain level of difficulty
and which type of garment you're
choosing in this tape.
It was sportswear, the main topic.
It's like the choice of the students.
And if you have to look at the taping, for example,
I guess it's super brilliant what
this student did in this case.
You also can go for super, super fancy 3D presentation.
You do not always have to think in the traditional style,
but you really can enhance your creativity.
This is also something I really encourage myself.
Thank you.
And now I asked some very classic questions.
Let's try to put a few head-on 여기서 to the camera
so that the shameless person
can see these match my students
to push their limits, to push their ideas and also
to push the software in order to get a better understanding
of what is possible so far.
This is something my students did in 2021.
So this is something like industry
is trying to achieve right now, and I can tell you it's possible.
If my students can do this, industry Hardwa,
I don't know.
Yeah, actually, this was one of the clips my students did in the industry project 2020 to 2021.
I guess you already see this is like two years ago. And this is what these type of students were already capable of.
I take these roughly old examples to.
To show how capable digital technology and 3D technology was already two to three years ago.
Right now, we can achieve even more because computation power is even better.
The algorithms are even better, which means that the type of garments, the creativity and
like touch and feel that you can realize is so much better.
Even now, then these students did experience in 2021.
But if you have a close look at this, I would say this is already some kind of brilliant.
And I guess everyone can understand the value these technologies have on teaching.
And I also think that you can pretty easily understand how proud my students were of her work once they were finished.
And I think you can easily learn something new about this project.
Which means that once again, others can appreciate it.
Because I was so impressed with the project like this.
This type of project was we are having industrial projects.
Which means in the sixth semester, like pretty at the end of the studies, the students have for 15 week weeks, the target to work on the issue.
Provided by industrial partners.
They do this like 20 hours per week.
And these is a part of the results.
My students did in this context.
partner in this type of project. The task was to develop digital collections in full
creativity and to do as much like visualization particles as possible. One chart outlook is
like in the digital world today is just like the tomorrow of yesterday, which means
that we really do focus on improving our workflows. This means we really do consistently work
on workflows. The one you're seeing here is that we are using Blender, Autodesk, Visu
for asset generation like we do all in this workflow of the 2D pattern development as
well as in Silo and do also there the 3D simulation. And then you can just decide
to publish for which one in Unity. You can build up some AR apps or 3D viewer apps. You can go for
KeyShot for rendering. You can go for Blender like an intermediate renderer or intermediate tool,
or you can just render and publish out of Silo. For example, right now you have super much or
super innovative solutions in Closet. Also since like the last days when it comes to AR, this is
one of our workflows. We are working on a lot of different workflows. We are working on a lot of
different models. We are working like on multiple ones. And I really do focus on making my students
understand the value also of these ones. Yeah, actually, from my part, that's it. I really,
really would like to thank you for your audience. And I hope that I could give some insights of our
work, that I could inspire your work a little bit. And if you have any questions also like in the
next days or weeks, please feel free to ask them in the Q&A box. And if you have any questions,
also like in the next days or weeks, please feel free to ask them in the Q&A box. And if you have any questions also like in the next days or weeks,
I guess Elaine, she will provide my contact data. Feel always free to just go in touch and ask me.